<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Spencer Karau</title>
    <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Spencer Karau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:34:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thesis Defense</title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/thesis-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 09:34:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/thesis-defense/</guid>
      <description>I successfully defended my Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis on November 28th 2024! My immense gratitude goes out to my supervisors, examiners, family, friends, and fellow lab members. I could not have completed this immense task without your assistance and support! Please see below a video that goes through my slides. If you would like to receive a powerpoint copy of my slides, please email me and I will be happy to send it to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2024 Annual CSEE Conference in Vancouver, BC</title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/csee2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 19:31:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/csee2024/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the oppurtunity to attend and present my thesis research at the Canadian Society of Ecology and Evolution conference held at the University of British Columbia. I had an incredible time in BC and had the chance to meet many amazing individuals! If anyone would like to get in contact with me further, please do not hesitate to reach out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invasive Species Forum 2024 Presentation</title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/invasive-species-forum-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 15:20:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/invasive-species-forum-2024/</guid>
      <description>Please find below a copy of a presentation I gave at the virtual invasive species forum on February 15th, 2024. I recently had the opportunity to speak at the Invasive Species Forum! This was my first time ever taking part in an online conference and I had a great experience.
** Update February 27th, 2024 ** My presentation has occurred! Find below a recording of the talk:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Article</title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/my-first-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 16:44:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/my-first-article/</guid>
      <description>First article published as of 2023-08-22. This article stemmed from work completed during the first semester of my degree! Thank you to everyone who made this work possible. The paper is titled &amp;ldquo;On the effectiveness of public awareness campaigns for the management of invasive species&amp;rdquo; and was published in environmental conservation.
Abstract: Invasive species can have disastrous effects on the ecosystems they invade, requiring costly, labour-intensive mitigation. Public awareness campaigns are often used as a tool to reduce these species’ impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The plan for this site!</title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 22:14:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/posts/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>After two years of contemplating, I finally decided to try building a website. Gaining inspiration from the https://plantarum.ca/ website of my thesis co-supervisor, I decided to look into creating a static site with Hugo. I plan for this site to serve as a general directory for my contact information, CV, and newsfeed regarding what I have been up to!
I also hope to update this site with progress on my research over the course of the next year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:41:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Spencer. Thanks for checking out my site!
I am an ambitious data science professional well-versed in working with large datasets, breaking down information and communicating results clearly. I&amp;rsquo;m a practiced statistical programmer with experience using geospatial tools. I am an adaptable and driven individual with a strong work ethic and the ability to thrive in team-based or individually motivated settings.
I just recently defended my Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis at the university of Ottawa in the Kharouba lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 00:41:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spencerkarau.github.io/mysite3/cv/</guid>
      <description>CONTACT skara076@uottawa.ca • Spencerkarau@gmail.com • Ottawa, ON K2C-0T6
SUMMARY Ambitious data science professional well-versed in working with large datasets, breaking down information and communicating results clearly. Practiced statistical programmer with experience using geospatial tools. Adaptable and driven with strong work ethic and the ability to thrive in team-based or individually motivated settings.
SKILLS • Microsoft Office
• RStudio
• Statistical analysis
• GIS (ArcGIS, Leaflet)
• GitHub/Git
• Hugo
• PowerBI</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
